How will the universe die? There're
three big theories, and this one just
got some brand new evidence. So, we know
that the universe isn't just expanding,
it's expanding faster and faster. We can
see galaxies moving away from us, and
the farther they get, the faster they
go. If that keeps going, the universe
could expand so fast that gravity can't
hold anything together anymore, and
everything starts getting ripped apart.
That's the first possible end, also
called the big rip. But, some scientists
think it won't keep going. At some
maximum size, gravity will start
smooshing everything back together
again, crunching it down like the Big
Bang, but in reverse. That's the Big
Crunch. But, this third theory says that
everything will keep expanding, but stop
accelerating. Meaning that everything in
the universe will spread out, thinning
and cooling until it can no longer
sustain life or light. That's called the
Big Freeze. Don't worry, all of these
are at least this many years away. And
all of these theories depend on just one
unknown number, the energy in empty
space. So, right now, scientists are
studying this brand new data set to
learn more. To see it, subscribe.